<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name" >Definitiva</string>
    <string name="action_settings" >Settings</string>
    <string name="hello_world" >Hello world!</string>

    <string name="nj1a" >Pelagia noctiluca</string>
    <string name="nj1b" >Rhizostoma pulmo</string>
    <string name="nj2a" >Aequorea forskalea</string>
    <string name="nj2b" >Cotylorhiza tuberculata</string>
    <string name="nj3a" >Velella velella</string>
    <string name="nj3b" >Aurelia aurita</string>
    <string name="nj4a" >Chrysaora hysoscella</string>
    <string name="nj4b" >Porpita porpita</string>
    <string name="nj5a" >Carybdea marsupialis</string>
    <string name="nj5b" >Physalia physalis</string>
    <string name="nj6a" >Olindias phosphorica</string>
    <string name="nj6b" >Mnemiopsis leidyi</string>
    <string name="nj7a" >Phyllorhiza punctata</string>
    <string name="nj7b" >Cassiopea andromeda</string>
    <string name="nj8a" >Salpa democratica</string>


    <string name="ij1a" >High</string>
    <string name="ij1b" >Medium</string>
    <string name="ij2a" >Low</string>
    <string name="ij2b" >Low</string>
    <string name="ij3a" >Low</string>
    <string name="ij3b" >Low</string>
    <string name="ij4a" >High</string>
    <string name="ij4b" >Low</string>
    <string name="ij5a" >Very high</string>
    <string name="ij5b" >Very high</string>
    <string name="ij6a" >Very high</string>
    <string name="ij6b" >No danger</string>
    <string name="ij7a" >Low</string>
    <string name="ij7b" >Low</string>
    <string name="ij8a" >No danger</string>


    <string name="j1a1" >Pelagia noctiluca</string>
    <string name="j1a2" >Mauve stinger</string>
    <string name="j1a3" >Danger</string>
    <string name="j1a4" >\n The stinger produced by Pelagia usually produces immediate pain with urticarial and edema. Also burning, vesicles, papules and scabs may appear and remain. Itching is typical. After-effects may be scars or keloids.\n </string>
    <string name="j1a5" >Distribution and Habitat</string>
    <string name="j1a6" >\n Widely distributed in warm and temperate waters of the world’s ocean. In the early eighties, Pelagia was very abundant in the Mediterranean, then disappeared and reappeared at intervals more or less than ten years, but since the warm year 2003, its presence is almost constant in the western Mediterranean. It is typically and offshore species, although they can reach the coastline, especially in midsummer, when they can form extensive banks that lash the coast for months.\n </string>
    <string name="j1a7" >Frequency</string>
    <string name="j1a8" >\n In the Catalan coast can be very frequent in spring-summer, although some years, depending on the environmental and weather conditions, they can be absent in the majority of beaches.\n </string>
    <string name="j1a9" >Characteristics</string>
    <string name="j1a10" >\n It usually presents a brilliant pink and mauve colour. The semi-spherical umbrella can measure between 5 and 20 cm. The umbrella is armed with eight long marginal tentacles, that extended, can reach up to ten meters, and the mouth is equipped with four long and thick oral arms. The surface of the umbrella is covered with brown warts. Pelagia, as other jellyfish, has the ability to bioluminescent or produce light. As the arms of Pelagia are very thick and dense, if they arrive at an aquiculture system, fishes in the farms can be killed. Given that this species also eat fish eggs and fish larvae, the impact on fish stocks and fishery can be devastating.\n</string>
    <string name="j1a11" >It is considered one of the most abundant and important species along the Catalan coats, and the vast majority of jellyfish’s stings recorded along the bathing season are attributable to this species.</string>


    <string name="j1b1" >Rhizostoma pulmo</string>
    <string name="j1b2" >Barrel jellyfish</string>
    <string name="j1b3" >Danger</string>
    <string name="j1b4" >\nWhen Rhizostoma stings, a moderate pain with burning sensation is commonly sensed. Local symptoms include local hives, sneezing, and eye irritation.\n</string>
    <string name="j1b5" >Distribution and Habitat</string>
    <string name="j1b6" >\nIts distribution includes the North and South Atlantic Oceans, the Mediterranean, the Black Sea, and the Red Sea. In the Catalan sea this species is considered as a coastal species. The small jellies are produced in spring and the big adults are more evident in summer. Usually recorded at or near the water surface.\n</string>
    <string name="j1b7" >Frequency</string>
    <string name="j1b8" >\nIt lives in abundance along our coast.\n</string>
    <string name="j1b9" >Characteristics</string>
    <string name="j1b10" >\nIt is the biggest jellyfish in the Catalan coast. The diameter of its bell-shaped umbrella can reach between 10 and 40 cm and can weigh up to 10 kilograms. The colour is milky white or slightly blue with a violet ring along the edge of the umbrella. This species lacks marginal tentacles, but it present eight thick oral arms; inverted Y-shaped fuse together and with no branches, which are also white-blue colour. Other organisms, like fishes and small crabs, may use this species as shelter, and are transported by the currents between its oral arms. The bearing of Rhizostoma is majestic, and the movements are slow and mighty. For many people of Southeast Asia, especially the Chinese, it is considered a delicious dish.\n</string>

    <string name="j2a1" >Aequorea forskalea</string>
    <string name="j2a2" >Many-ribbed jellyfish</string>
    <string name="j2a3" >Danger</string>
    <string name="j2a4" >\nHarmless to humans, although it is better not touch it.\n </string>
    <string name="j2a5" >Distribution and Habitat</string>
    <string name="j2a6" >\nIt is distributed throughout the Atlantic and Indo-Pacific Oceans, in all suitable temperate to tropical waters, occurring occasionally even in mid-ocean. Inhabits coastal and offshore waters.\n</string>
    <string name="j2a7" >Frequency</string>
    <string name="j2a8" >\nIn the Catalan coast during last year has become a frequent species, and when occurring it does in large numbers.\n</string>
    <string name="j2a9" >Characteristics</string>
    <string name="j2a10" >\nIt presents a transparent plate-shaped umbrella, which can reach up to 17 cm in diameter, with a denser mass in the centre. It is distinguished easily from the other jellyfish due to many blue radial channels that connect the centre to the margin of the umbrella. It has numerous thin marginal tentacles and no oral arms. This species has allowed the isolation of the green fluorescent protein (GFP), a substance at the base of the fluorescence of many jellyfish. The discovery of this protein has allowed us to develop new techniques for the diagnosis of diseases and the research in the field of molecular biology. This discovery has led to applications in the diagnostic field, allowing us to mark specific cell lines. The discovery of the GFP was worth American researchers Osamu Shimomura, Martin Chalfie and Roger Tsien the Chemistry Nobel Prize in 2008\n</string>

    <string name="j2b1" >Cotylorhiza tuberculata</string>
    <string name="j2b2" >Fried egg jellyfish</string>
    <string name="j2b3" >Danger</string>
    <string name="j2b4" >\nHarmless to humans, although it is better not touch it since some skin reaction can be detected.\n</string>
    <string name="j2b5" >Distribution and Habitat</string>
    <string name="j2b6" >\nIt is a very abundant endemic species in the Mediterranean. It is a coastal species, showing some preference for warmer waters.\n</string>
    <string name="j2b7" >Frequency</string>
    <string name="j2b8" >\nIt is very frequent in the Catalan coast; the adults are seen in highest abundances in late summer/early autumn.\n</string>
    <string name="j2b9" >Characteristics</string>
    <string name="j2b10" >\nThe umbrella that can reach between 20 and 35 cm is flat except for the centre, where a prominent formation extends from the bell. The oral arms are short and present three button-shaped appendages in the extreme. The umbrella has a yellow-brown colour, with dark orange or reddish colour in the rounded centre, and the tentacles are white with blue-violet endings. It is one of the most beautiful jellyfish of the Mediterranean. Cotylorhiza may present microalgae that live on its own tissues in symbiosis, just as the coral formations of tropical coral reefs. Functionally, then, you can define it as a plant even they feed on zooplankton. As Rhizostoma, is often associated with fish that adopt this species as a refuge.\n</string>

    <string name="j3a1" >Velella velella</string>
    <string name="j3a2" >By-the-wind Sailor</string>
    <string name="j3a3" >Danger</string>
    <string name="j3a4" >\nHarmless to humans, although it is better not touch it. \n</string>
    <string name="j3a5" >Distribution and Habitat</string>
    <string name="j3a6" >\nOccurs in warm and temperate waters of all the worlds’ oceans, and it is very common in the Mediterranean. It lives at the water/air interface, with the float above the water, and polyps hanging down about a centimetre below. It may be present in huge swarms reaching even several kilometres. As their movement depend totally on currents and surface winds, they can be show-up to the coast and be found stranded in the beaches.\n</string>
    <string name="j3a7" >Frequency</string>
    <string name="j3a8" >\nAlong the Catalan coast, as in the whole Mediterranean basin, are very frequent, especially during springtime.\n</string>
    <string name="j3a9" >Characteristics</string>
    <string name="j3a10" >\nIt is not a medusa stage of a jellyfish but a floating colony of hydromedusae polyps. The colony, that forms a blue oval disc, is about 1_8 cm, and the blue polyps are attached to a chitinous float equipped with a sail that carries the colony with the aid of the wind. The colony, toward the end of its life, which lasts for a few months, produces jellyfish of a few millimetres.\n</string>

    <string name="j3b1" >Aurelia aurita</string>
    <string name="j3b2" >Moon jellyfish</string>
    <string name="j3b3" >Danger</string>
    <string name="j3b4" >\nThe poison of Aurelia is harmless to humans, although it is better not touch it. In some people skin reactions were observed.\n</string>
    <string name="j3b5" >Distribution and Habitat</string>
    <string name="j3b6" >\nAurelia lives in all the oceans of the northern hemisphere, where it can be very abundant. Generally, it is an inshore species and can even be found in estuaries and harbours.\n</string>
    <string name="j3b7" >Frequency</string>
    <string name="j3b8" >\nAlong the Catalan coast, its frequency has dropped the last years, considered nowadays a low frequency species. When present, it can be often observed at the end of the spring.\n</string>
    <string name="j3b9" >Characteristics</string>
    <string name="j3b10" >\nIts plate-shaped umbrella can reach up to 25 cm. It is a translucent jellyfish, with violet gonads arranged in four circles in the centre as horseshoe-shaped, which are visible in transparency. From the manubrium, four long oral arms extend, and many short marginal tentacles surround the umbrella. Unlike other species, much more delicate, this jellyfish is suitable for living in aquariums and then can be observed in marine aquarium around the world. In China is a very popular dish.\n</string>

    <string name="j4a1" >Chrysaora hysoscella</string>
    <string name="j4a2" >Compass jellyfish</string>
    <string name="j4a3" >Danger</string>
    <string name="j4a4" >\nThis sting usually leaves erythema injuries, with maximum pain within minutes of the sting and often disappears two hours later. More severe symptoms have been reported only in few cases.\n</string>
    <string name="j4a5" >Distribution and Habitat</string>
    <string name="j4a6" >\nIt is a pelagic species that lives in the Atlantic and can be found in the North, like the Norwegian fjords, where it can reach enormous densities. In the Mediterranean is not plentiful, but it is frequently found.\n</string>
    <string name="j4a7" >Frequency</string>
    <string name="j4a8" >\nAlthough it may be very abundant in some Spanish Mediterranean areas, in the Catalan coast is considered as a species of low frequency. It is commonly observed in spring.\n</string>
    <string name="j4a9" >Characteristics</string>
    <string name="j4a10" >\nThis white-yellow color jellyfish has an umbrella that can reach 30 cm in diameter, and a manubrium with four oral arms that can reach a meter in length. The upper face of the umbrella is decorated with 16 brown V-shaped bands, which goes from the center of the umbrella to the margin, where there are 24 thin and long tentacles, in groups of three. \n</string>

    <string name="j4b1" >Porpita porpita</string>
    <string name="j4b2" >Blue button</string>
    <string name="j4b3" >Danger</string>
    <string name="j4b4" >\nBlue button jellies do not have a lethal sting, but they can cause skin irritation.\n</string>
    <string name="j4b5" >Distribution and Habitat</string>
    <string name="j4b6" >\nThis species is found in warm waters off Europe, in the Gulf of Mexico, the Mediterranean Sea, New Zealand and southern U.S. waters. These hydroids live on the ocean surface, but are sometimes blown in to shore, and occasionally seen by thousands.\n</string>
    <string name="j4b7" >Frequency</string>
    <string name="j4b8" >\nAlong the Catalan coast this species is very rare.\n</string>
    <string name="j4b9" >Characteristics</string>
    <string name="j4b10" >\nThis species is relatively small and may measure between 1 and 5 cm. They consist of a hard, golden brown, gas-filled float in the centre, surrounded by intense blue, purple or yellow hydroids, which look like tentacles. The blue button jelly is made up of individual zooids, each specialized for a different function, such as eating, defence or reproduction.\n</string>

    <string name="j5a1" >Carybdea marsupialis</string>
    <string name="j5a2" >Box jellyfish</string>
    <string name="j5a3" >Danger</string>
    <string name="j5a4" >\nAlthough Carybdea is a cubozoan, its poison is not lethal. The sting is very painful, with little pain at first and then severe, but the intense effects are short. Usually, bright red papules appear in the skin, and muscle cramps, vomiting, restlessness and anxiety may be observed in some cases.\n</string>
    <string name="j5a5" >Distribution and Habitat</string>
    <string name="j5a6" >\nCubozoans can be found in most tropical and subtropical waters, and especially Carybdea marsupialis has been found in temperate waters as well. It is likely that the distribution records are incomplete as the transparent nature of these medusae makes them very difficult to locate despite their shallow and coastal distribution. The preferred habitat this species appear to be over sandy substrate, located just above the bottom during the day and moving up toward the surface at night. Moreover, Carybdea is attracted by the light and approaches the coast during the night.\n</string>
    <string name="j5a7" >Frequency</string>
    <string name="j5a8" >\nThis species is present in high abundances is some areas of the Spanish Mediterranean coast, but along the Catalan coast is considered very rare, although its presence may be underestimated more than absent.\n</string>
    <string name="j5a9" >Characteristics</string>
    <string name="j5a10" >\nThis cubic shape species is very small, reaching approximately 5 or 6 cm. It presents a transparent blue or white colour and four long tentacles that extend from each side of the cubic umbrella. It swims in a very vigorous way, and it moves easily.\n</string>

    <string name="j5b1" >Physalia physalis</string>
    <string name="j5b2" >Portuguese Man-of-War</string>
    <string name="j5b3" >Danger</string>
    <string name="j5b4" >\nThis species have two different sizes of nematocysts (small and large) for stunning or killing prey. The sting of this species is intense with severe pain. A line of white oval papules in the centre and a red margin is observed in the contact area. In some cases, the encounter with Physalia can be lethal, and some rare overall effects include tremors, diarrhea, vomiting and convulsions.\n</string>
    <string name="j5b5" >Distribution and Habitat</string>
    <string name="j5b6" >\nIt is often found in warm, tropical and subtropical waters of the world’s oceans, however, there have been reports from beaches in England, Wales and Ireland. In general, it can be found in the Atlantic Ocean, Pacific Ocean, Indian Ocean and the Caribbean. It is a pelagic marine animal that floats in the surface of the sea and it is blown about by the winds and pushed around by the currents. It is most common in the open ocean, but currents and winds may direct them into shallow waters or wash them up on beaches. In the Mediterranean is not encountered frequently, however, some years we had numerous reports form the Western Mediterranean including waters from the Balearic Islands.\n</string>
    <string name="j5b7" >Frequency</string>
    <string name="j5b8" >\nAlong the Catalan coast is considered very rare, although some isolated observations have been reported in the last years.\n</string>
    <string name="j5b9" >Characteristics</string>
    <string name="j5b10" >\nPhysalia is not properly a medusa, but a colony of syphonophores polyps. In addition, they are not individuals, such as the jellyfish, but they are colonies. This species can be recognized by the bluish pneumatophore, or float, which can be up to 30 cm in length. This float is an overgrown polyp that is oblong shaped and filled with gas. The floats include a mechanism that controls the gas to regulate the depth of the organism, which keeps them on the surface of the water. The blue to purple tentacles, may reach up to 50 m length.\n</string>

    <string name="j6a1" >Olindias phosphorica</string>
    <string name="j6a2" >Cigar jellyfish</string>
    <string name="j6a3" >Danger</string>
    <string name="j6a4" >\nAfter the sting of this species, very characteristic zigzag red lines appeared in the skin. The pain is instant and intense.\n</string>
    <string name="j6a5" >Distribution and Habitat</string>
    <string name="j6a6" >\nIt is a hydromedusa with a broad global distribution, being known from temperate Atlantic waters and from the Mediterranean Sea. In recent years, it has been very abundant along the coasts of Tunisia in the Mediterranean, causing problems for the tourism industry.\n</string>
    <string name="j6a7" >Frequency</string>
    <string name="j6a8" >\nThe presence of these jellyfish along the Catalan coast is sporadic. It never forms extended bank, but can be locally abundant.\n</string>
    <string name="j6a9" >Characteristics</string>
    <string name="j6a10" >\nThis Mediterranean hydromedusa species is transparent in colour, and the umbrella can reach up to 8 cm diameter. Through the umbrella four radial canals arranged in a distinctive red cross-like pattern can be observed. Small red-blue tentacles surround the umbrella.\n</string>

    <string name="j6b1" >Mnemiopsis leidyi</string>
    <string name="j6b2" >Sea walnut, Comb jelly</string>
    <string name="j6b3" >Danger</string>
    <string name="j6b4" >\nAs it is not a cnidarian, but a ctenophore, it doesn’t have cnidocysts and therefore it is not poisonous. It is harmless to humans, but very harmful to the invaded marine ecosystems.\n</string>
    <string name="j6b5" >Distribution and Habitat</string>
    <string name="j6b6" >\nThis species is native from estuaries and coastal areas of the western Atlantic Ocean, from the U.S. coast to Argentina. In the early 80’s arrived to the Black Sea transported in ballast water of American tankers, and had expanded since the last three decades to almost all Eurasian waters, including the Mediterranean basin. Records from the western Mediterranean first appeared in the year 2006, and in the year 2009, it was first recorded in Catalan waters.\n</string>
    <string name="j6b7" >Frequency</string>
    <string name="j6b8" >\nThis invasive species was first reported in the Catalan coast in the year 2009. Nowadays, its presence is intermittent in some parts of Catalonia, but in the southern area, especially in the Ebro Delta coast, there is an established population that is under a rigorous study in order to determine possible invasion effects.\n</string>
    <string name="j6b9" >Characteristics</string>
    <string name="j6b10" >\nMnemiopsis leidyi is a ctenophore and not a cnidarian, but is included in the jellyfish group due to its gelatinous consistency. It has a lobed oval-shaped body that can reach up to 12 cm in length. It is transparent in colour, and presents four rows of ciliated combs that run along the body vertically and glow blue-green when disturbed. This species does not swim with the pulsations of the body (as jellyfish do), but the eight ciliated bands while beating, propel the movements. In the Black Sea, where the ecosystem was already weakened by pollution and overfishing, Mnemiopsis leidyi has depleted the fish stocks by eating eggs and fish larvae and also the prey of planktonic larvae. We do not know if its impact in the Mediterranean will be such as that suffered by the Black Sea, therefore rigorous research is taking place in the Catalan invaded area in order to predict and estimate the invasion impact.\n</string>

    <string name="j7a1" >Phyllorhiza punctata</string>
    <string name="j7a2" >Australian White Spotted jellyfish</string>
    <string name="j7a3" >Danger</string>
    <string name="j7a4" >\nThis species deals no painful stings and therefore does not constitute a threat to the bathers.\n</string>
    <string name="j7a5" >Distribution and Habitat</string>
    <string name="j7a6" >\nPhyllorhiza punctata is a coastal and estuarine jellyfish whose wide native distribution includes Australia and much of the Indo-Pacific including the Philippine archipelago.\n</string>
    <string name="j7a7" >Frequency</string>
    <string name="j7a8" >\nA Along the Catalan coast the presence of this species constitute and invasion, and in the year 2010 was first reported in the southern coast of Catalonia with no further records until now.\n</string>
    <string name="j7a9" >Characteristics</string>
    <string name="j7a10" >\nIt is a large jellyfish with a rounded and somewhat flattened umbrella which diameter can reach up to 72 cm, with a clear colour or possibly tinted brown with many small crystalline refractive spots close to the surface and uniformly distributed. It lacks marginal tentacles, but eight highly dichotomous oral arms ring the central mouth area, that each bears 14 lappets (flaps of tissue) and become fused near their bases. It feeds on plankton of crustaceans and, probably, of eggs and larvae of fish, being therefore, both a predator and a competitor of fish and can cause the depletion of the seas. A few years ago has invaded the coast of Florida, causing a sudden collapse of the marine fauna. As Rhizostoma, is edible.\n</string>

    <string name="j7b1" >Cassiopea andromeda</string>
    <string name="j7b2" >Upside-down jellyfish</string>
    <string name="j7b3" >Danger</string>
    <string name="j7b4" >\nIt is not dangerous, but it is better not to touch it because it produces mucus in which the cells presents poison, and if you enter in contact with it, you may have skin irritation.\n</string>
    <string name="j7b5" >Distribution and Habitat</string>
    <string name="j7b6" >\nIts native range includes the Indo-Pacific waters, typically found in shallow lagoons, intertidal sand or mud flats, and around mangroves. The entrance to the Mediterranean was through the Suez Canal, inhabiting nowadays some areas along the Mediterranean coasts.\n</string>
    <string name="j7b7" >Frequency</string>
    <string name="j7b8" >\nThere are no records of its presence along the Catalan coast.\n</string>
    <string name="j7b9" >Characteristics</string>
    <string name="j7b10" >\nThis species usually lies mouth upward on the bottom, gently pulsating its bell to create water flow over it’s arms. It is small in size, reaching a maximum of 30 cm diameter, and with a yellow-brown colour in the umbrella with white or pale spots and streaks. The outstretched arms are also brownish with extended frilly tentacles. This facing upward allows unicellular algae, such as those of the corals formations, to live in symbiosis with the medusa.\n</string>

    <string name="j8a1" >Salpa democratica</string>
    <string name="j8a2" >Salp</string>
    <string name="j8a3" >Danger</string>
    <string name="j8a4" >\nSalps don’t have cnidocysts; therefore they are harmless to humans.\n</string>
    <string name="j8a5" >Distribution and Habitat</string>
    <string name="j8a6" >\nIt is a globally distributed species, mainly found in subtropical and tropical waters. It usually form very extended banks that spread away from the coast.\n</string>
    <string name="j8a7" >Frequency</string>
    <string name="j8a8" >\nIts frequency along the Catalan coast may be variable, and usually observed during springtime when gelatinous blooms are common in some coastal areas.\n</string>
    <string name="j8a9" >Characteristics</string>
    <string name="j8a10" >\nIt is a barrel-shaped planktonic tunicate, with a clear orange stain visible due to the transparency of the body. It has a solitary life history phase, which is known as an oozoid, and the chain of these oozoids is the aggregate portion of the life cycle. The chains (or colonies) may reach even 6 meters long. Population explosions of these animals are sudden but they last only a few days.\n</string>

    <string name="it" >Treatment</string>

    <string name="tt1" >Jellyfish stings: what you need to do</string>
    <string name="tt2" >Jellyfish are invertebrates that float in the sea. They have stinging cells to capture prey and defend themselves. In recent years the frequency of jellyfish blooms has sharply increased.</string>
    <string name="tt3" >What to do if a jellyfish stings you?</string>
    <string name="tt4" >What to do when there are jellyfish on the beach?</string>
    <string name="tt5" >Jellyfish stings</string>
    <string name="tt6" >How does it feel when you get stung?</string>
    <string name="tt7" >People who might be at greater risk</string>
    <string name="tt8" >How to avoid jellyfish?</string>
    <string name="tt9" >If I see a jellyfish in the distance, may I dive?</string>
    <string name="tt10" >May jellyfish cause death? </string>
    <string name="tt11" >May mild stinging jellyfish be touch?</string>
    <string name="tt12" >What is the jellyfish stinging liquid made of? </string>
    <string name="tt13" >Do natural remedies work?</string>
    <string name="tt14" >Do the anti-jellyfish glasses, masks and costumes help?</string>
    <string name="tt15" >Are the anti-jellyfish lotions useful?</string>

    <string name="t1a" >What to do if a jellyfish stings you?</string>
    <string name="t1b" >\n Stay calm, breathe normally, leave the water immediately, and wash the affected area with seawater. The seawater is essential for cleaning the skin and washes the pieces of jellyfish that may be stuck to the skin and for diluting the toxin that has not penetrated yet.
    1. Wash with seawater
    2. Remove rest of tentacles with gloves or tweezers
    3. Apply hot compresses (no more than 45ºC), of not possible, then apply cold compresses
    4. If the pain persists, apply Lidocaina
    5. Apply antiseptic in the wound until it heal
    </string>

    <string name="t2a" >What should I do when there are jellyfish on the beach?</string>
    <string name="t2b" >\n
    - Do not go swimming.
    - Do not walk along the shoreline where the waves break, as half-buried jellyfish remains also sting.
    - Do not touch any jellyfish, even if they are dead.
    - If you see one in the sea, slowly get out of the water without making any sudden moves. Jellyfish never attack people.
    - Use suntan lotion as a preventive measure.
    </string>

    <string name="t3a" >Jellyfish stings</string>
    <string name="t3b" >\n Contact with jellyfish tentacles
    -in or out of the water- causes a painful burning sensation that could last for days or weeks.

    Stings cause a rash that can reappear several times.

    Take into account that if you have been stung before, you will be more sensitive to new stings. A second sting could cause a much more serious reaction.
    </string>

    <string name="t4a" >How does it feel when you get stung?</string>
    <string name="t4b" >\n
    · What to do if a jellyfish stings you?

    · A local inflammatory reaction that gives burning and pain. "The skin is red with small hives, but after 20 minutes, the burning sense is attenuated and remains the itching sense," explains Francesco Sacrini, dermatologist at the Clinic Institute Humanitas, Milan. The degree of pain varies depending on the affected area, and becomes unbearable if more than 50% of the body surface is affected.
    </string>

    <string name="t5a" >People who might be at greater risk</string>
    <string name="t5b" >\n
    - Children.
    - People who suffer allergies (atopy, asthma).
    - People with severe cardiovascular diseases.
    - People who have been stung by jellyfish before.

    It is advisable for people who are more sensitive to stings to take extra precautions and, where necessary, visit a medical centre.
    </string>

    <string name="t6a" >How to avoid jellyfish?</string>
    <string name="t6b" >\n Looking at the sea: if they are present, they can be normally seen and the only way to avoid them is not bathing. Jellyfish do not attack us and go for us. Jellyfish move vertically in the water column, therefore they may be on the surface or in the bottom. They are animals that move but are also carried by the currents and winds. There are no predefined rules: they are everywhere because they are part of the plankton and the currents drift them.</string>

    <string name="t7a" >If I see a jellyfish in the distance, may I dive?</string>
    <string name="t7b" >\n If there are stinging jellyfish in the sea is better not to swim, unless they are really few. Jellyfish that sting hard, usually have very long tentacles: Pelagia noctiluca, for example, can reach up to 10 meters long, while Phisalia physalis (Portuguese man-of-war) can reach 20 meters.</string>

    <string name="t8a" >May jellyfish cause death?</string>
    <string name="t8b" >\n Yes, some may cause anaphylactic shock. Moreover, sting sharp pain may be fatal for people with heart problems. Therefore, we must go to the lifeguard station in case of diffuse cutaneous reaction, if you have difficulty breathing, sweating, pallor, and disorientation. Ferdinando Boero says: "In Australia, jellyfish cause more victims than sharks. In Florida, the Portuguese man-of-war has also caused victims. But to date in the Mediterranean, there have been no victims at all, although many people stung by jellyfish end up in the hospital."</string>

    <string name="t9a" >May mild stinging jellyfish be touch?</string>
    <string name="t9b" >\n Better not, although its venom is almost harmless for us. Even the tentacles of harmless jellyfish, have cnidocysts (small cells containing the poison), which may remain in the palm of your hand and if you do not wash it and then have contact with the eyes (or other delicate parts), we may transfer the poison and cause inflammation.</string>

    <string name="t10a" >What is the jellyfish stinging liquid made of?</string>
    <string name="t10b" >\n From a mixture of three proteins: one with paralyses effect, another with a neurotoxic effect and a third with an inflammatory effect. There are no specific antidotes for these poisons - however, they are heat sensitive, i.e. they degrade at high temperatures.</string>

    <string name="t11a" >Do natural remedies work?</string>
    <string name="t11b" >\n Is it good to apply a stone or hot water, rub with hot sand, washed with ammonia, urine, vinegar or alcohol? These remedies are not only useless, but may even worsen the situation. The heat of a stone or sand is not enough to override the 40_50 degrees that should be reached to stop the toxin. The content of ammonia and urine doesn\'t deactivate the toxin, and may even cause further inflammation in the affected part.</string>

    <string name="t12a" >Do the anti-jellyfish glasses, masks and costumes help?</string>
    <string name="t12b" >\n Swimming with glasses or mask help to look and see the dangers under water, and wetsuits can protect the skin. Also, the new anti-jellyfish wetsuits designed and produced in Australia are useful, and may be found in Spain for sale on-line.</string>

    <string name="t13a" >Are the anti-jellyfish lotions useful?</string>
    <string name="t13b" >\n Sacrini explains: "The anti-jellyfish lotions were created considering the security mechanisms used by the clown fish [fish that has a jellyfish repellent substance.) Anti-jellyfish lotions, currently on the market, are associated with sunscreen. They are based, as described in scientific articles, mostly on 4 principles: make sure the skin is slippery and therefore prevent the tentacles from landing; confuse the recognition mechanism of jellyfish (also composed of water and GAG); block the activation system of the stinging cells; and struggle against the osmotic pressure within the nematocysts. It has a different answer depending on the species of jellyfish, the right application and the time spent in water.</string>

</resources>
